hello thanks for tuning in and this is
kind of a different video that you're
about to watch where normally I I have
dialogues with people and record them
and then post them this one is actually
a recording of me giving having a
circling method session within my
training course from a few years back
so I teach and I've been teaching a
year-long intensive in teaching people
how to facilitate in lead circles in the
circling method and this is the third
weekend in which I'm in the course was
were able to video in a really high
quality video because circling is is
really difficult to capture but I think
this one did a pretty good job and so
what you'll be seeing is is me giving a
demo working one-on-one with Vanessa who
is who is in the course and then you'll
see my training partner John and in
kelowna
John cotton who's there kind of giving
the play-by-play and pausing things and
teaching and then you'll see everybody
sitting around watching and taking notes
and stuff like that what's a little bit
different about this circle is that it's
it's the context is just her and I and I
don't include the group where normally
there's a group of people and we include
we I include them and we work with the
whole group but this is just one I want
however I think it really is a great
demonstration of what's possible through
circling and through the practice as
well as is it starts to get into what I
would call what we've been calling its
dialo goes right which is where it's not
just the dialectic inquiry the
back-and-forth
but there's something there's a third
factor that emerges right where and this
in this particular one you can really
get the sense that not only were we in
much with what was most essential and
undescribable like Vanessa's suchness
but in a way that evoke a sense of the
greater mystery of everything the
inexhaustible the more Ness at some
point is the circle goes on you can kind
of see how it starts that that awareness
that intelligibility that orientation
starts to become both background and
foreground and eventually start to brew
like bleed into each other
so enjoy it's a really rare it's a rare
thing to get this on camera and be able
to get it in a way that actually shows
it and I think if this one does a pretty
good job if you are interested in in and
partaking in the art of circling in what
you can becoming a part of what you see
here we are we have just announced and
just started enrolling people into the
first art of circling all online I think
we have a special for the first 15
people who register there's a discount
and I think it's about how or about
halfway there so I think we're about
seven or eight something like that at
this moment last I checked so
information about that are links below
and information to all of our courses at
the circling Institute is below also if
you want to work with me one on one a
little bit like what you see here go
ahead and email me and we can go over
the cost and and the details of that
okay enjoy and of course if you want to
get notifications for all of my videos
go ahead and subscribe there's a button
right down here and please feel free to
share this video to your friends and
family and whoever you think this would
they would like it and it would serve
them alright thank you
Hey so let's um so we'll go it's going
to do a demo so like just stop at any
point and you can if you want to point
something out or map it all out and I'll
stop and and talk about things as well
and well like we'll take advantage of
any kind of warrior moments but like I
don't never I've never noticed it never
really works to let go for a particular
aspect so basically we're just gonna
circle yeah throw it stinky better
everyone close your eyes home base first
sovereignty kneel
feel your breath since your sensations
feel your butts in your chair on my
floor feel your lap your thoughts and
take another deep breath and just kind
of feel that kind of essential you and
as we do slowly open your eyes in a
while staying home just look around the
room and say literally and like
ritualistically just acknowledge other
we
and then everyone bring their attention
to this fountain of cotton consciousness
and then take a bulb and just like
brutally breather and drinker and like
kind of like she's whining just notice
the impact
and it's just one word I just want to
start with everyone just like one word
whatever's there for you just just as
you bring your attention to her just one
word that's there no I'll go first
Wonder
keep going
do
divine
worse
there
bird-of-prey
Hey
I notice there's moisture coming up DRS
like two or three different occasions it
seems like there was why they're
happening there what is the weather like
I'm sitting here hearing these words
coming from other points of
consciousness and it's like seeing the
contrast between my own thoughts with
myself so just system of the emotion
came up when you felt the contrast
nobody hurt between like what you would
think or what you and maybe say a or
implicitly or explicitly and what you
you heard from them something about that
contrast like broke up in love or how do
you feel love all the stuff although all
the words I have with myself to try to
contain this image that I want to make
hold on to and it's like so violent
so so it's like you felt sadness if you
felt loved and he felt loved and then at
the same time or closely after that
there's this sadness for the lack of
love for myself so yeah this thing what
is this thing the thing
yeah the thing he held up your hand you
like that's like my self-image like what
I have to contain to exist in the world
- like exists within myself so I don't
disappear oh okay that struck me
you know like a little electric bolt
that was through me like this image I
have to the word I have to maintain in
order to exist I just got the sense of
look at this sense as you're talking
that this has been kind of an
interesting weekend free to hunt it's
been pulling together like all the sort
of thoughts study like I've been paying
attention to what you're posting and
I've been thinking about it I've been
thinking about the Indian I've been
thinking about how I apply the order and
the chaos and like where I live
I've been thinking about the different
facets of my personality that keep me
safe and in the walls of safety and in
order so yes this has been it's been
like really validating and like bringing
more layers of insight that so I'm
feeling excited like I I'm really
excited to like feel that bottom line
like what it feels cross over that that
like structure of myself into like who I
really am and I think I've been I've
been searching for that my whole life
and I'm just seeing like all the
subconscious like stuff that I've sort
of been doing and
and see how
not useful it is
but there's still this grasping of like
wanting to exist like wanting to still
exist in this lake that's a cold world
this one second
this struck me wanting this sort of
grasping of wanting to exist serious
like the the twinkle in your eye no like
a little background smile that's it see
this occurred to me through almost like
a through line through everything that
you've been talking so you've been
talking just made sense to me it's
almost it's almost like it's it's
interesting my experience is almost like
almost like you feel like you're getting
away with something right great yeah
it's like that is this there's this joy
you know like what I'm hearing you say
is like you're all you talking about
things like kind of yeah I feel like
what I've considered myself to be I'm
gonna annihilate it right in fact I kind
of want to write and goddess sucks but I
feel loved and like whoa this is intense
but I would do it I I pay for it I pay
to do it again or something totally
totally so that right there let's I just
want to feel that with you what is that
what's the texture of that
what was that what he just did that was
war here right like that's Alexis's
worried before he lost her and this was
just that right there noticing something
and he's holding that moment anything
else you want now just holding the
moment okay
what is the texture wonder yeah like I
just know like I have this knowing that
there's so much potential in human
beings like there's so much more
underneath the personality right and
that's why this weekend is so exciting
for me and I feel like I'm at like the
tip of the mountain like in my my foot
is stuffed over but I haven't fallen yet
and I'm just like so excited to fall
like to have that experience so you're
like so a couple of things you're
actually in the presence of wonder so
the texture of this feeling like what's
behind that smirk right the thing that
you're getting away with it feels like
an accomplishment huh I was surprised to
hear you say that just like an
accomplishment
the feeling of Wonders accomplishment
what's the accomplishment get into the
excitement of it like I'm just excited
to like usually it's terrifying to go
into something that you're scared of
okay so pause one second say it's
panicky that seems that strikes me as a
big deal like so something I've been
terrified of before I'm actually excited
about
mm-hmm that's just like I just might
have revered that for a moment so I was
like what is that like for you just like
so if I point that out and say like okay
who's just mirror back to you it's like
I'm excited about my own like
transmutation if you will
it hasn't totally happened yet right
like I like I don't I don't know exactly
where the unknown is but when I find it
I'm gonna step over it right but I'm
excited about it
where I used to be terrified
what's it what is that does that mean
something to you I feel a sense of
meaning about that what does that mean
to you just that change that changing
orientation right yeah to me it means
like my ability to be with like whatever
is you know like it's sort of like
taking a crazy psychedelic drug you know
it's like it's terrifying but if you can
be with it say this I just love it like
you say it's terrifying like this is
there is something there's someone to
wisdom in the terror so much wisdom you
know like if you were like pay attention
to it like what what's so scary and then
what I keep finding is that it's not
that's scary
it's just life itself happening
okay gotcha says so you just I think I
just got a peek of what's like what's
what the transformation is is like so is
what I heard you say is that like like
when a peak right when I peak it's
impossible my own transformation right
at life like when I actually look what I
find is not the thing that I was
necessarily terrified but I just find
life itself and there's something about
that it's life itself and that
recognition that has do you say things
like I'm terrified right and you smile I
I'm presented this kind of paradox this
growing paradox what I'm seeing and just
like this kind of like this complex
feeling in myself
what's happening for you
at this very moment like we like hearing
you like I I almost went out like I
wasn't it's like it was like a little
like flicker of something like came into
my consciousness and I was like oh it's
really important right there okay that
that responds to a flicker in your
consciousness that this is already out
by the time you look at it that that
eagerness like so I get the sense of
disliking it's not like the flicker
happened and you looked at your like
well upon reflection I think I'll be
don't like that there's just a pre
reflective that's the thing I want to
get close to I notice with you yeah yes
I could get this sense of just like
almost like there's something in the
background that's just listening for
like listening I don't know for like in
that sense of like where you're in a
crowd you're gonna be in this crowded
chaotic place and if you hear your own
name there's like like all the animals
Hashmi like all like something's
listening such that what I hear it-it's
but I realize like oh I've been
listening the whole time for something I
just get that sense with you yeah I'm
enjoying that reflection like I'm
thinking about being present with that
like maybe that's where I really am
it's like I just wanted I want to create
space for the awesomeness of it I had
this sense that we were actually like
when you talked about going over the
clip I did since I think we're already I
think we are falling it wasn't sure and
it's different than I expected expected
to kind of like fumble through like more
of my darkness but like what I'm
experiencing right now is my light what
I'm experiencing right now is my life so
has me just like so they just notice
he's a little pre reflective like little
moments of wonder to what just what's
happening like does that bring my
attention to it you're like oh maybe
actually I've already like I already am
that maybe that's what I am
what does that feel like
feels like it's always been there and
it's never abandoned me ah so there's
this way and we're like it's me this is
who I am and it's been Who I am and in
this way it's me
and it hasn't abandoned me I feel and I
feel kind of like almost like I trans
personally held or something yeah that's
like
yeah really
they're like I'm kind of tripping on the
bone right surreal
what I heard do you say actually is it's
like you're realizing like the twelve
dis surreal is what I'm hearing you say
is actually what's most real it's like
most thing like this little sliver and
I'm having deja vu or now as I'm talking
about this just makes it even more weird
but like there's a sliver of my like
being that's like I just got a glimpse
elf and like there's all this stuff that
was like in my way of like seeing truth
and like who I am and like it's still
holding all this crazy shit to like all
one still that's all of it thank you so
when it is like I want to so basically
we're heard you say it's like whoa
actually I've already jumped in fact I
am a jumper right the fact I've been
falling and jumping and in wonder the
whole time in such a way that I've I
haven't that it's never abandoned me
even when I haven't known about it as it
required me even knowing about it in
fact it's even not knowing about it
being mistaking itself and it still
hasn't left me and as you realize this
you feel moved things feel trippy and
then I get interested in the trip penis
and it seems like it's like I say well
it seems like if that's actually what
you're saying is actually the trippy is
what's real and then you hone in and
you're like yeah like I can I can I can
kind of see see the light if you will
and there's everything that felt like
not that but somehow when I look at it
like that it still it's all been that
the whole time
I'm impressed with my ability
paraphrasing like it's just there's a
sense of I think it's I think it's where
my attention goes a lot of times
naturally encircling is like kind of
there's a way in which I'm like
listening I'm listening to you
alrighty then let's see other person
what they're saying in a personal level
but there's also this other piece where
I'm just kind of just that there's
something there's something unfolding
right it's like almost it's like prior
to its prior to my awareness its prior
to in that whatever that whatever that
that thing that's unfolding seems to
seems to have some kind of logos do it
or some kind of order but I I feel more
inclined to like discover something that
is true right discover something that's
true with you so I think if I listen to
it's like that like if it's like where
my attention is going is this kind of
like one is really understanding you but
also being present to just what's at the
tip of what you already understand or
you haven't put into words yet and then
noticing being with you in that like I
guess like with the with the doubt like
you know just kind of being being at the
edge of something new and then like then
you say it and then mean paraphrasing it
and then we both get to have this
experience of like being surprised by
what is happening yeah can tickles and
it was yeah it was way more than
paraphrasing so like I was paraphrasing
but like getting her like current world
or the world that she's speaking but
then as you're doing that you're
you're like trying her on and you're
you're getting with you kidding a you're
saying more than she said so you're
feeling into like what it's like to be
her and then sharing so you're getting
her world on that level it's going
beyond paraphrasing and then like you
said you're even then imagining okay so
given that she's so I heard what she
said but now trying it all on like what
hasn't she said but I'm still getting
and so so he trusted his intuition and
he just went like deep into the story
like as far down as he would go in the
moment and just shared all that as he
was paraphrasing so you it's like looks
like you didn't just do it in steps
which is sort of all doing it at the
same time
yeah but the key to me was that you
would you were trusting yourself just to
tell a deeper story that hasn't been
told yet even if you were not right yeah
and and that's so like the warrior part
of seeing what hasn't been seen yeah
and so now you're seeing it together and
whether it landed or not it landed so
psyched well that's beautiful but even
if it didn't she would have had to go
down there to find something else
glad you said that I think trusted but
actually am i trusting though like you
know I don't know if I don't doesn't
feel like I'm like trusting my ability
to be accurate or something it's more
like I'm trusting my intention actually
I'm trusting that you understand my
intention right and that's this I think
that's the thing where I feel free to
like take your awareness and like put it
inside my nervous system and go because
it is it's kind of like there's so much
reality and I only have one mouth so
it's like you can only talk about so
much of it and then I could I can just
I'm here with it like we're both sharing
an awareness yes it's like the
acknowledgment of that there's that
we're sharing awareness right yeah it's
almost like I have to trust that you're
gonna take like my data and put it into
your computer and
[Laughter]
so it's like you're not you're not
trying to serve them so obvious yeah
yeah I didn't feel like I was being
circled I felt like I was having a
conversation like a deep conversation
good guy which is like an honor to me
getting that insight
yes I had one last thing I also like how
God uses like he uses his body as a
barometer number of times you said wow
that really struck me this is one of the
places I know this dissonance probably
most of the circle this is where
somebody says something and they say it
you know usually we think of dissonance
as they say like something in their
angry but you're smiling and so you hear
an emotion but the body language is
different
but what I noticed that the most is when
the lack of emotion they say it
matter-of-factly
what it strikes that's the point
oh my god like what you just said impact
even though it's you seem to be just
nonchalant with it and each time I
noticed you pointed that out what struck
me
this f is going to disappear I've been
searching my whole life searching that
my whole life wanting to exist oh wow
that really struck me and then that
strikes me as a big deal you're excited
where you used to be terrified and it's
just coming up with stuff like yeah I
just liked letting that hit you and then
just having the faith that that what
you're gonna share is he's talking okay
I keep getting this sense of like a I
like a historian bullying or something
yeah I'm just thinking of the earth like
I'm just like from that experience I
just had and applying it to like this
like feeling that I can disappear or not
exist and then I'm like so that that
felt sense of that wonder like if that's
who I really don't and then I'm like
taking that and then putting it in these
like areas of my life where it feels
unworkable or undoable or hopeless or
something and like putting that
wonderment in there was like oh if that
wanders there then like I'm still
existing in the way that matters most to
me
and if you move by you're tracking like
wait you're paying attention to what I
heard you say it was like basically
basically yeah
Wonderman and then there's this this
place where I like I fear not existing
right and like not wonder well what
happens very like I want to tease you
about Minnesota Midwestern enlightenment
drag Lake what happens when I take this
and I put it in just that suggests that
whatever it is like ha I think the thing
that I'm most I want to feel I want to
get close to you with you it's how did
you know to do that didn't like it
strikes me as just that's something that
Claire not everyone does that just the
inclination to know oh and then put it
in there is that is actually it's like
it's like you know is that the is that
to you that we were talking about that
you've been the whole time that didn't
need you to know about it such that you
realize it never abandon you is that the
wonderment yeah
that part of me that's never like I get
I've gotten curious about every single
experience of my life like I never
ignored anything curious whatever every
single experience of my everything yeah
I mean like at the earliest age that I
think I could like I would lay in bed
when I was five and like try to imagine
what it's like like to not exist like
what is death like you know so I think
it's just something that I've been doing
my whole life like oh let's take that
and put it there so just get this it
this image just you and a certain sense
this Wonder has been like kind of like
this silent partner mm-hmm and I think
it's where I it's like my joy like I
remember my very first circle someone
getting mad at me when I was suffering
and I was like smiling at the same time
and this person like had a really bad
reaction to that and I was like well
it's because I am like I get excited
when I get to go into this dark scary
area and like explore it it's like
that's who I am like just I'm so curious
and especially when it's like me and now
it's like oh no it's a really cool to
[Laughter]
just like the thing you did like
especially as me oh and now I can point
it now I can what I heard you say is
what I'm kind of getting is like so
we're recognizing something together
right like it's like it's Ricky guys me
almost like a secret
no I didn't know that that wonderment
was so important that I didn't identify
with that I guess they identified with
like all the stupid crazy shit that I do
for my personality and yes the
wonderment is sort of like the observer
- maybe there's like 3000 facets of me
there's like the one who's curious the
one who observes the curiosity and the
chaos like the craziness so I almost
feel like there's I just met another
piece of Who I am or another so as we as
we meet it meet this other piece of you
it does feel like this I feel in a
certain sense like we're both if I'm
holding you to something it's like and
you just have this quality of like it
just like slip out of your hands if you
don't hold it right or something if you
clench to it like I get that sense of
like I don't want to like make it too
mechanical or too specific but I do feel
like I'm somehow relaxing with you into
this deep consideration this profound
consideration - - that may be actually
what I what I've wanted to be is
actually when I've been the whole time
and like what happens who knows if it's
true
like I'm hearing that implicitly there's
it you know that it's true there's also
the feeling like almost like that would
almost be a violation of the of you to
say and I know it's true yeah cuz all
the shit that's take you know like and
then I also think about okay if that's
true and like that's the me that's
always been there it's like how do I
make that little sliver of light the
bigger piece of a picture versus like
the crazy shit it's like right now if
there's like a rectangle and like the
real me is like this little sliver like
there's all like I want to make that gap
bigger and have like the craziness part
got smaller yeah it is wondering this
one this wonder bug that you are right
once things and that's what I really
just heard is like not like I'm just
wondering would actually like I want I
want I want everything wonders so it's a
different way I heard that differently
than what you just said another version
or easier said how do I make this when I
stick it in there but now I just heard
another version of like actually I want
all of this to be that I want to that
gap might to be wider so if we say if we
say that like here we are and like what
what in this moment what is or what
isn't what is or isn't included right
now you said that there's stuff over
here right that like although I realize
it's all one thing I haven't totally
realized it's all one thing it's still
like I look over there and there's is
you said that there's the the character
of my personality and its various
complaints and laundry lists and things
I need to get over so that I can
whatever that is right and then there's
this right that moving it over what
right now in this moment like is this
whole moment is isn't wonderous for you
are there parts where it's saying wow I
don't actually I'm not very connected
with it what's it like hearing like is
it all I can say in response to that is
that I wonder
see pause for one second hold on okay so
it's like it's my the pot a great day so
that's that's a distinctive thing that
like if I just was following the
movement of where things were going
right it's like there's this deeper
question and like now I could feel this
sense of like alright so like in a
certain sense
I'm taking your aim and I'm like just
making it explicit and bringing in it
now and in that moment like this is
gonna be probably a bunch of other stuff
that comes up right it's kind of a
warrior moment if you will yeah and I
also over here I feel like uneasy like I
am feeling like I don't totally
understand what you're saying and I
didn't totally understand what you're
saying twice that's like okay all I can
do is say like what I'm thinking
he said fine so pause right there okay I
don't ask you something - so you seem to
be like really really tuned into the
moment yeah you're also pulling stuff
out that's stuff you're getting about
her like that's outside the moment now
are you consciously aware of like
everything that's happening in a circle
and you're sort of following the
connecting the dots or you're just
staying in the moment and this is just
coming to you like how are you doing -
do I think it's like I think I would
imagine something like um those things
that you wrote down I like little I
think there are little testimonies of
like kind of themes or what I'm getting
so I think those things kind of hold a
bunch of a bunch of specific things that
you said so they're like threads and so
when there's this bigger sense of like
alright I am Wonder right I recognize it
right I realize it but then there's this
other part which it's like but then
there's my life because that contrast
and then I want this to be like that in
some way and so I'm like just noticing
if I follow the movement of that like
holding that so something is me is just
tracking kind of I think themes or
threads and like bringing them in and
just feeling kind of the movement of it
and but the thing I'm kidding you're
like right now what's it like being
confused
okay so I'm confused doesn't like you
said something about like I did boy I
didn't understand you didn't understand
me twice
yeah right and that's something
something is I'm not confused about that
I'm just like this like like I'm getting
that there's something I don't want to
hear whatever your question or whatever
you say like I'm just I'm just aware
that there's maybe a block or block is
here yeah there's some maybe you're
taking me in a direction that I'm having
some subconscious resistance to yeah so
what is it what is it like what's your
response to seeing the possibility of
everyone totally totally so there's a
curious is this like if there's that pre
reflective response right I'm curious
and it's and it's like not necessarily
good news okay oh I'm blocked about
something right and I'm curious so
here's a moment where it just happened
spontaneously no smiling yes so so it
sounds like it's like as the thing I've
been noticing through the circle it is
like when I make something I think
implicit like explicit and show it to
you there's this Glee that this joy and
you talked about it seems to happen it
didn't enjoy factor what
I'm noticing that my body is shaking I'm
like uncontrollably shaking
so let's like uncomfortable yeah
when you said that I it like I felt a
little bit like if I put myself in that
position it's basically only I feel out
of control is it like that kind of
uncomfortable yeah I like wanting to
control it yeah there's a shaking like
where's the curiosity with that no
sensing is much there's something
bubbling I'm afraid I don't know there's
just I think I'm feeling a little
frustrated because I just want to I want
to get there shaking I just like I feel
just like a lot of joy and you just your
desire just and it's also like I've said
this before it's something about like is
this way in which like the word pump
comes up with you lot like there's like
come on like let's get on with it we've
been talking five minutes already let's
dissolve for Christ's sake why do I have
to shake okay right in fact I'm shaking
because like you're kind of guy you're
kind of getting in the way you're saying
confusing things or whatever like taking
a long time like so there's a sense of
impatience yeah totally now that when I
feel that sense of impatience is right
it's been a hangout there for most so if
we're just gonna but we're just kind of
people welcoming everything that's
happening impatience is here
I'm getting curious about I I just have
this sense of like if we were to open up
what in patience is I have a I just have
this sense that there's a there's been
some kind of relationship with
impatience that we could probably have
would probably tell a story about I mean
I'm just like kind of going I sit around
kind of impatient all the time like I'm
expecting some grand finale and it
doesn't necessarily look like anything
but maybe a sense of accomplishment and
I think I do have a fear that like once
I experienced that its depth the
impatience what's that death like I
leave my body like it's done man like
this existence is done moving on to the
next when when the grand finale happens
and I and it's weird because I have this
like impatient feeling like would that
to happen for the grand finale yeah and
then but it's weird because after that
would come death piece of this Susie
well now maybe sense because like I
think I do have like this weird death
wish
but am I really afraid of it - you're a
trip okay
they do these turns like these turns it
you're making like I had no idea you
were gonna say I think I'm deathless and
it's in such a matter-of-fact way that's
one of the things that's striking and it
feels to me unique but one of the ways
that you occur to me is unique like just
make sense it used it oh yeah I think
actually thanks okay like something like
yeah laundry grocery list death wish so
that so so as I feel into it if there's
dissonance for me I think I've just I
started to hit some of it right like
like so there's this one part was what
you said about the wonder it's also what
you said about the impatience huh I
think it's always here I think it's
always here and I just all of a sudden
they saw the wonder on the right side
and the impatience on the other
and as they say that holy shit happens
let's take a moment and let's actually
see if we can leg together and maybe not
maybe not necessarily be in wonderment
or impatience but just like to see it
and see what happens
don't think I know how not to being
wonder there so I don't know it doesn't
seem like it's like almost like we don't
I don't know how I don't think there's a
joint there to move yeah I think it's a
me it's just you it's like my essence
just do something or like a facet of
minimal right I obviously see myself
like in the in-between world at this
like little glowing ball like bouncing
around like in wonderment yeah totally
except for something it's something
about impatient seems like something
other than that glowing ball oh yeah
it's like that when you've said that I
was like oh that's all that you see of
the economy it's like it's a big part of
it yeah and like that's all like the
death wish seemed like somehow plays in
right I got you it's hard it's like so
right now it's like so right here so
here's that like if I look if I look at
like we're live now okay the struggles
live how do I get the impatience to fit
into the light like or get them wonder
to fill the impatience part like this
stuff
one of the ways that we entered into
that it sounds like is when you started
to shake when you notice that you're
shaking right yeah when I got what are
you fed up with I just felt my heart it
surprised me how it is
thus we Genesis brought up her me leg
and kind of setup what the human design
oh my god
it's like all makes sense but it's hard
hey fuck it I just totally unfolded and
you said I stopped shaking a little bit
it's hard it's hard to like have the
design of like feeling your separate
when you know you're not it's hard to
like feel lonely when you know there's
no reason for it like it's hard to like
see the whole big picture you know like
and I just see it it's hard to like hold
it all and like and then live in this
world where even talking about something
like that is you know it doesn't get
validated
I feel
okay feel like almost goosebumps
reversed or something I feel this really
in darken bumps or something like it
feel fiha at the sense of like deep
person like a deep personal sense of
when you said like it's hard I did they
was like I felt like I felt something
being knowledge that like unfolded me
like so I'm like sitting like this and I
just said you're talking about like God
yeah it's so hard like to know you have
to feel something different than I know
I kind of like how do I ever bridge that
gap right yeah so I just I think as I'm
talking right before when we started
talking about I was like oh I got I get
hit with this like sense of like
compassion or warmth that was just it
just spontaneously there and there's
some folding thing happen and then and
now there's this place where I think
what I think what we're touching is like
this is a place that you just your human
being the suffering huh
there's a way that like even even
knowing the ultimate the ultimat thing
to be wonderous about like it's even in
some way having the one being wonder
itself affords the everything but then I
find myself as someone who's just as
something in while holding the
everything and it creates this whole
thing that goes on and it's so personal
I feel disconnected to you personally
right now
I understand impatience from here
actually is one response to the
suffering both is a response to it and
also like an expression of it and as I'm
sitting here I'm just noticing as I'm
top as I'm working through my experience
I just got hit with the view because I'm
making sense of myself with you
I am like I feel really really
profoundly in the presence of just
loving you
and almost like I like I wouldn't solve
it but I just do feel like I like just I
love like as if I ever could felt like I
really feel like it wouldn't what's it
like to hear just like my experience of
you
is it okay if I touch you
it feels good to have like that
untouchable of speaking full like
thinking that with something other than
main wonder
it's something I do you have some level
of like belief that no one else will be
covering that and you just comprehended
it it's like really complex thing to me
I feel like I could see here with you
for like ever actually and it's all like
super exciting it's hard to share it
it's like it just goes over people's
heads and I'm weird I feel honored to I
did it's really interesting like it's
say as you say like um sees I feel like
I'm just gonna underneath this tree or
something it's like we just solved some
Kohan there's anything and we ended up
like right where we were but just
weren't ordinary or something but
somehow it's more profound but I also
just like I'm as I'm talking now I'm
just I feel like as I'm talking I'm
touching closer into this displaces
thing that you said like I I'm it's so
it's so I don't know what the word but
they're so rare where it's never
happened I think
the thing is complicated things of being
me that I can't it's unspeakable right
that I'm being mad the first time not
just by my wonder but my love and it
happens to be a person
and this is the place where it's like so
personal if you need to happen there's
been no person where it's most personal
for you to get here I don't think I've
ever heard anyone say that to me
to die together
so so what's it like not being dead and
being here
hard to describe like I don't even know
I said I don't know we talked about just
having the experience it was kind of
cool it was like having someone here
with you is that you don't have to hold
all that I can just yeah what you said
you said is like essentially you could
see right here is like yeah I am
wonderment but like with that wonderment
being a human being with a name and like
and age and desires and concerns in
Minnesota and like off like all of its
right like that it's not like it's like
one the wonderment and being a finite
human being it creates this this
dissonance as chord dissonance between
what I know and what I kind of
experience or than I am and that like
that if like as I go through life that
dissonance has takes a toll on me and
one of the tools it takes is so fucking
complicated like if I try to share it I
lose people right which which in losing
people like it's there's a sense of I
haven't ever eaten had them in the first
place right so this deep the thing
that's most important to me this
wonderment than I am is like unbeatable
with in fact I thought that in order to
transcend all of that or like to get
close to all that I just needed to get
rid of the part that like I get so
fucking impatient with and so therefore
it's like that's the wish I wanted is
just like can't we just hurry up and
just
I and on some level if we say like like
was like you somehow somehow we ended up
underneath this tree together and you
didn't die and like you're here and
you're being touched by something other
than just the wonder remember yeah and
it feels like it's a sort of like
something I thought never happened so
happening is going on that is exceeding
your thoughts it's like chaos how come
I'm smiling
you're gonna because you just taught us
about order and chaos let's see if I am
I just I think I just felt actually a
reversal there of like before you're
talking about like what I know in
reality like don't match like I know so
much more than what I can experience
what I heard you just say here is like
I'm I think I just all I'm experiencing
so much more than what I know yeah
I just had like that my chills just
reversed again I mean it's pretty
fucking awesome that I get to know
something I didn't know and I get I get
to know that I don't have to die in
order to like he understands like on
this really deep real level for me that
like probably seems really unreal the
most people unless you do like massive
amounts of acid or something
so as you're talking like the thing that
you've been doing the whole time when
you've talked about the wonderment you
looked over here I mean you talked about
your lighted like everything else and
over here yeah and like right now like
you're looking at watching you move your
eyes and you're like and you're
basically going like wow I'm like I
think what I'm seeing is you starting to
be find the wonderment over here you
went really deep you like this so you're
an amazement is it close like you're in
amazement of life like here we so here
we are life like like you know biology
your biology I'm growing old you're
growing old like all the stuff right at
some point I'll say something that
you'll get impatient about nope it's
like all the stuff right gravity physics
all that like but it's like it's what
I'm hearing you say it's a great in this
moment like it's life is actually
presenting something more than you could
comprehend like here we are like
something never even being considered a
mystery with you you couldn't like you
can't you know you can't comprehend that
you didn't even know to probably want it
here it is no I mean this skill is
really unique you don't find it in the
world you know and like that's why I'm
here like that's accessing areas that
you just don't know what's it
amazing like I feel like it like rewires
the brain like it does this like real
physiological change like that moment of
like getting that I don't have to die to
be met in this way that felt unbeatable
changed every cell in my body like I
have new eyes I feel like I'm sitting
and listening to the profit of the
profane did you guys feel like staff
that sat down there's some business
thing to you
thank you for doing that so I like it
like it did to put any boundary around
this moment like just feels it's just
absolutely ridiculous to me like
if we were if we were to wind open this
this circle is this a good place to
start winding it open anything can you
think more that you want to stay
I I just hope that I can like hold on to
the snowing I guess I still don't know
what just happened and I hope that I can
like weave feeling that madness suppose
most second cities women so okay so
you're having an experience that you
don't that is actually like that you
don't know I don't trust it because it's
like I see like that that death wish I
do things that like kind of cause death
right and like those are the things that
I want to get out of my life so it's
like one of the places when I'm hearing
is like one of the places I want to eat
I like so what I'm hearing is the urge
to integrate actually an urgency like
when I heard that thing is like actually
not just the earth but the urgency to
integrate thank well I'm hearing you say
is like God if I could have infinity now
like in all areas without having to die
part of me doesn't totally believe it
when I ask myself but there's this thing
that I just happened right here that I
didn't know about so maybe I want to
learn how to not die right so I can have
what's happening PS hurry up hurry up
and integrate before you die kill
yourself I just I think it's like it's
so so while I I feel like there's this
on this ride with you that was so
surprising right just like whoa and like
he's still telling at the end of it
you're like alright hurry up whatever
that that was that thing is resilient to
all of that like I'm not even like no
I'm not even not dying for fundly like
affected that thing that's like all
right listen I want more than appetite
yeah that to me to me how I'm
experiencing that is like that is a you
there's a way that runs through you
that's really unique and it sounds like
it sounds like it like it's irritating
to you or it feels irritating or
something like that but for me it's just
like it's just like the KERS is a unique
and unique you I feel I feel blessed by
[Music]
so I'm getting that you see kid now
she's paraphrasing me I know yeah I want
to understand my youth you see how that
annoying urgence is like maybe a unique
kind of cool things about me versus like
just play mine I feel I feel delighted
by it something about that seems like
maybe affecting you
I'm delighted by something that is bad
hmm no that seems like that could be a
whole nother circle that we're not gonna
have
[Laughter]
seems like so much to track what what
are the curtsy me is like maybe less
than half the way into the circle it
went beyond warrior and the whole rest
of the circle is like deep dive which is
next weekend
just stay there it just kept going
deeper so I was noticing I I had an
intention to like stop you more often
and in the deep dive it just by 2 inch
to
so just stream of consciousness thoughts
here please Michigan should we take a
break and then go over this you think or
like what's the okay okay so let's go
over a little bit and we go over to get
after less you want to you need it right
guy yoga are you guys okay for 10
minutes so do we need to take I said do
it now well it's ready okay that was it
thank you so early for you you would you
didn't notice dissonance a lot and the
thing that I noticed about your noticing
is that he would not only would he never
make her long for dissonance but he
would celebrate the distance it's
terrifying
like when she smiles I was terrified and
you just sort of mimicked her but like
not really mimicked her but like
celebrated her expression yeah and then
like you didn't even have to say it was
dissonant like she just got it and that
sort of open the door for something
something new and I really appreciate
how you you act out moments of her way
of expressing herself again like both to
appreciate her and so she can sort of
see herself in your
did you guys notice for making a lot of
times recovery canal and also how you
would naturally mirror her I don't think
you ever even intend to do it but a lot
of the second half of the repose of the
circle you were and she was like rubbing
her face and you were kind of like right
there noticing some evidence of deep
rapport also in just the way that he was
was finding those notes of humor that
she liked there was something about that
that he was so attuned to her humor as
well that every time that we would laugh
together I felt like oh there's more
trust in room there's no true and Trust
in the room and so like that level of
the tune it was happening as well what I
want to be is what I cleaned the whole
time and
it could have been like advice or it
could have been like I want to reframe
your experience so you feel better
but it was really like a question mark
and getting getting where she was at
right at that moment with the
possibility of expansion and you know
I've seen you in other circles spend a
ton of time sharing than that like you
share impact more than probably anybody
ever seen it's like a lot of times you
just constantly sharing and using your
body to share how you feel and this
particular circle you didn't do that
long so it almost seems like it just
wasn't necessary like really what was
called for was more sort of being in her
world
I think it's actually it felt like a
certain point it just felt like yeah I'm
looking at something of like the impact
was just being explicitly happening just
like she was seeing she's yeah yeah yeah
sort of extra need to be more
consistently getting the world yeah
because it was like it like it kept
drawing I like bigger and more personal
dimensions at the same time that like I
actually needed to but I needed to get
it to be able to like be to stay up with
the conversation basale and it also
occurred to me yeah that's act alone is
what made me feel like love that he
liked because it was kind of hard to
comprehend so you just kept going and
then there's a point where you said
what's it like to be confused and again
that's just like guys willingness to
just take a risk like if a brand new
circle II was doing that we might judge
them we might say you're making an
assumption but because he because the
place he comes from is not that I'm
making an assumption said I'm a Co
exploring your world where you come from
is more important than doing something
right and so in a sense he made an
assumption like you what's it like to be
confused she said I'm not confused and
so as a circle a circle or he could have
been embarrassed in that moment he could
have felt guilty he could have
apologized and instead what'd he do he
laughed and he said so I'm confused and
the other thing if that's not your
personal reaction the other place you
could go with that is say the simple
questions so
and it's another similar thing a bit
where you would just be with her in a
way that opened the door for something
more you say
I'm so sorry enlightenment again he
could have said you know enlightenment
doesn't follow a schedule and then it
would be giving advice but it's like he
was like he was getting a piece of her
world with you or and opening it so he
was still getting what's real for her
like that was a true statement
and he wasn't judging it and he was
opening the door for her to see her to
see it more broadly wandering patients
together is bringing notes to like
anytime you see two things that like two
different things going on which is like
presencing they're close together and
just holding that dichotomy for them
that's that's a powerful to me that's a
powerful warrior moment to it's holding
in that way
I'm just saying it's hard it's pointing
to that I wrote down something I
selfishly wanted to say to you in that
moment which was when you said it's hard
what like occurred to me was it's it's
hard to be a soul in a soulless world
and and to be aware and and so like the
question that I was imagining is like so
do I want to continue becoming even more
where when I know how hard it is but
then you seem to get like you got to the
essence of all that was like the final
phase of the deep dive going into the
birth of you and again just like using
both humor and tenderness in the same
moment it's so powerful
because it's like such a release and I
love like you do that a lot that you're
circling it's like so what do you like
about something what's it like to not be
dead and your response was I don't have
to die I realized I don't have to die to
be met in this way so I have new eyes
birth to something new
so the way you got you really got a demo
of the next two weekends with some
warrior in the beginning the second is
that was equated listening to all that
was really really big but it does kind
of disappear like at least in the way of
like honest it's hard to kind of track
and remember the specifics of those
things but like you're saying it
I like the to change that like I think
the key for me was I do think there's
this way in which like would speak to me
are these themes like these almost
existential themes right of like
personal and wonder if like you know
impatience and wonderment and these
kinds of things it's just like something
about those that lacks land to just
pointing those out and then displaying
them like seemed to be just on its own
something that happens it's like neither
you or me but like it's almost like a we
I think it seems to be a part of the
relationship the relationship starts
informing us and your way of tracking it
is it's awesome I think that's something
that's just you can't even you can't
even plan for it you just have to
continue just have to circle a thousand
times and then that sort of seeps in but
like you you wrapped up the whole circle
and sort of tracked or we capped the
whole circle but you could have never
liked if a court reporter was there
riding out the circle it didn't sound
anything like what you would have gotten
from that it's like you took the essence
[Music]
so we often think a warrior old harps
not going to be a warrior so there's a
lot of ways it's nice to go into warrior
like we did this weekend get confronted
by it and grapple with all the ways to
say I don't believe you it would be
harsh and then getting soft
so
you